<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jubilant Ingrevia Ltd. on Financial Report Insights</title>
    <link>https://reports.muthu.co/tags/jubilant-ingrevia-ltd./</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jubilant Ingrevia Ltd. on Financial Report Insights</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 11:11:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://reports.muthu.co/tags/jubilant-ingrevia-ltd./index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Jubilant Ingrevia Ltd - Jan 2025 Earnings Call Transcript Analysis</title>
      <link>https://reports.muthu.co/posts/jubilant-ingrevia-ltd---jan-2025-earnings-call-transcript-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 11:11:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reports.muthu.co/posts/jubilant-ingrevia-ltd---jan-2025-earnings-call-transcript-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;earnings-call-transcript-analysis-report&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Earnings Call Transcript Analysis Report&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#earnings-call-transcript-analysis-report&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;financial-performance&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Financial Performance&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#financial-performance&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Revenue:&lt;/strong&gt; Q3 FY25 revenue was Rs. 1057 crore, up from Rs. 966 crore in Q3 FY24. This increase is attributed to higher year-on-year revenue from Specialty Chemicals and Nutrition &amp;amp; Health Solutions segments.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EBITDA:&lt;/strong&gt; Q3 FY25 EBITDA was Rs. 148 crore, a 9% sequential increase and a 42% year-on-year increase. Growth was primarily driven by margin improvements in Specialty Chemicals, better mix, and cost optimization.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Net Debt:&lt;/strong&gt; As of December 31, 2024, net debt was Rs. 684 crore, with a net debt to EBITDA ratio of 1.36 times (trailing 12 months EBITDA).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capital Expenditure:&lt;/strong&gt; Q3 FY25 CAPEX was Rs. 92 crore; YTD (first nine months) CAPEX was Rs. 299 crore, primarily funded through internal accruals.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Net Working Capital:&lt;/strong&gt; Net working capital percentage to turnover for Q3 was 18.4%, down from 22% in Q3 FY24. Days of working capital reduced to 67 from 80 days in Q3 FY24.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PAT:&lt;/strong&gt; Q3 FY25 PAT was Rs. 69 crore, up from Rs. 39 crore in Q3 FY24, an 80% year-on-year increase.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interim Dividend:&lt;/strong&gt; The board has recommended an interim dividend of 250%, which equates to Rs. 2.5 per equity share with the face value of Re. 1 each for FY25, resulting in a cash outflow of Rs. 39.8 crore.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;strategic-initiatives--business-updates&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Strategic Initiatives &amp;amp; Business Updates&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#strategic-initiatives--business-updates&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New cGMP Vitamin B3 Facility:&lt;/strong&gt; Commissioned a new cGMP compliant vitamin B3 facility in Bharuch, Gujarat, to produce nutraceuticals and dietary active ingredients.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global Lighthouse Network Award:&lt;/strong&gt; Received the &amp;lsquo;Global Lighthouse Network Award&amp;rsquo; from the World Economic Forum, recognizing the Bharuch facility&amp;rsquo;s integration of Fourth Industrial Revolution Technologies.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pinnacle 345 Vision:&lt;/strong&gt; Committed to growth plans to achieve its &amp;ldquo;Pinnacle 345 Vision&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost Saving Programs:&lt;/strong&gt; Key efficiency initiatives delivered substantial annualized savings of over Rs. 120 crore from Surge, Lean, BE and Energy Saving programs. Phase two of the cost program is launching.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agrochemical Plant Upgrade:&lt;/strong&gt; CAPEX has commenced for upgrading the existing agrochemical plant to fulfill a five-year agreement with a multinational agro innovator.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Renewable Energy:&lt;/strong&gt; Targeting to move more than 30% of power requirements to renewables in FY26.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;market--competitive-landscape&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Market &amp;amp; Competitive Landscape&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#market--competitive-landscape&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chemicals Market:&lt;/strong&gt; Globally, chemicals markets are witnessing gradual volume improvements, but pricing is staying muted in most segments and regions. Expect volume growth to continue, but price recovery may be slow.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pharmaceutical Market:&lt;/strong&gt; The pharmaceutical end-use market continues to see steady demand, bolstered by stable pricing and volume placements.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paracetamol Segment Challenges:&lt;/strong&gt; Encountering challenges in the Acetyl business due to low demand in the paracetamol segment.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agrochemical Sector:&lt;/strong&gt; The agrochemical sector has continued its upward momentum in this quarter, driven by positive volume growth. However, average prices in the sector have remained flat.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nutrition Market:&lt;/strong&gt; The Nutrition market experienced a continued resurgence in demand. Niacinamide volumes remained stable with a slight price increase during the quarter. Choline demand saw stronger growth, however, faced pricing pressures from imports.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Market Share in Niacinamide:&lt;/strong&gt; Maintained top two leadership position in feed grade Niacinamide.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Market share in Choline Chloride:&lt;/strong&gt; Maintained number one position in the dry Choline chloride market.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Market Share in Acetic Anhydride:&lt;/strong&gt; Retained market share in the acetic anhydride market while increased shares in both ethyl acetate and acetaldehyde segments.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;risk-factors--challenges&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Risk Factors &amp;amp; Challenges&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#risk-factors--challenges&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Low Demand in Paracetamol Segment:&lt;/strong&gt; Acetic anhydride volumes were muted due to low demand in the paracetamol segment, impacting Chemical Intermediates business.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pricing Pressure in Chemical Intermediates:&lt;/strong&gt; Prices in the Chemical Intermediates segment remained under pressure, significantly impacting margins.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pricing Pressure in Choline Products:&lt;/strong&gt; Pricing remained under pressure. Expect revenue and margins to increase in coming quarters due to the new cGMP plant commissioning, increasing volumes of food and cosmetic-grade vitamin B3.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Logistics Costs:&lt;/strong&gt; Higher logistics costs associated with export sales impacted the Chemical Intermediates business.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;forward-looking-statements&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Forward-Looking Statements&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#forward-looking-statements&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overall Business Performance:&lt;/strong&gt; Anticipate continued improvement, upward momentum and improvement in overall business performance in the ensuing quarters.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q4 FY25 Outlook:&lt;/strong&gt; Expect improved sequential performance in Q4 FY25, driven by new plants and operational efficiency.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CAPEX Plans:&lt;/strong&gt; Plan to announce the launch of more CAPEX projects in line with the long-term growth strategy.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Semiconductor Segment:&lt;/strong&gt; Hoping to get the first commercial order in FY26. Expect a separate P&amp;amp;L for that business with commercial orders coming in and gradually ramping up.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Renewable Energy:&lt;/strong&gt; Targeting to move more than 30% of power requirements to renewables in FY26, which will significantly contribute to the reduction of scope 2 emissions and reduce power costs in coming quarters.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;qa-insights&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Q&amp;amp;A Insights&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#qa-insights&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Specialty Chemical Margins:&lt;/strong&gt; Management expects Specialty Chemical margins to remain at least at 23% to 24% EBITDA, even with potential volatility in Pyridine and Beta prices.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chemical Intermediates Recovery:&lt;/strong&gt; Expects the Chemical Intermediates business to take a &amp;ldquo;couple of quarters&amp;rdquo; for paracetamol problems to resolve and for cost initiatives to take effect.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vitamin B3 Capacity Utilization:&lt;/strong&gt; Expects to fill up the capacity of the new vitamin B3 plant in the next 12 to 18 months.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CDMO Contract Milestones:&lt;/strong&gt; The CDMO agro contract is on track, with milestones being met, and the plant is expected to be commissioned by December or January of the following fiscal year (FY26).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dividend Policy:&lt;/strong&gt; Management&amp;rsquo;s focus is on reinvesting in the business for growth.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;management-tone--sentiment&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Management Tone &amp;amp; Sentiment&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#management-tone--sentiment&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overall Tone:&lt;/strong&gt; Cautiously optimistic. Management highlights positive performance in Specialty Chemicals and Nutrition, while acknowledging challenges in Chemical Intermediates.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Confidence:&lt;/strong&gt; Management expresses confidence in the growth trajectory of Specialty Chemicals and Nutrition, supported by new facilities and strategic initiatives. Also confident about achieving &amp;ldquo;Pinnacle 345&amp;rdquo; Vision.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Caution:&lt;/strong&gt; Management acknowledges ongoing challenges in the Chemical Intermediates segment, particularly due to weak demand in the paracetamol market and pricing pressures.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost saving:&lt;/strong&gt; Focus in increasing the profitability of the business via cost-saving initiatives.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;button-container&#34;&gt;    &#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jubilantingrevia.com/Uploads/files/16q2consfileearnings-calls-transcript.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; class=&#34;report-button&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-file-pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Download Transcript&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jubilant Ingrevia Ltd:Annual Report 2023-24 Analysis</title>
      <link>https://reports.muthu.co/posts/jubilant-ingrevia-ltdannual-report-2023-24-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 23:28:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reports.muthu.co/posts/jubilant-ingrevia-ltdannual-report-2023-24-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;jubilant-ingrevia-ltd-a-comprehensive-overview&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Jubilant Ingrevia Ltd.: A Comprehensive Overview&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#jubilant-ingrevia-ltd-a-comprehensive-overview&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;about-the-company&#34;&gt;&#xA;  About the Company&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#about-the-company&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year of Establishment and Founding History:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Formerly Jubilant Life Sciences, the demerger led to the formation of Jubilant Ingrevia in &lt;strong&gt;2021&lt;/strong&gt;. The original company, Jubilant Organosys Ltd., was established in &lt;strong&gt;1978&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Headquarters Location and Global Presence:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Headquarters: &lt;strong&gt;Noida, Uttar Pradesh, India&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Global Presence: Operates in global markets, serving customers across various geographies. Specific details on country-wise presence require more data.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Company Vision and Mission:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
